## Summary

I am a User Experience Designer with over eighteen years in interactive media. My career spans the breadth of digital production, from production art to web design and front-end development. As a User Experience Designer, my in-depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints.

# **Professional Experience**

## KBS (Kirshenbaum Bond Senecal)

March 2015-present

**Associate Director, User Experience** 

**KBS** 

November 2016-present

- Leading a design discovery for the website redesign for PODS. Delivering a UX audit, competitive research, personas, journey maps, and usability testing
- Designed a 3D cabinet configurator for *Stanley Black & Decker*. Created a design system, user flows, usability tests, and comprehensive prototypes
- Built a skills matrix for the UX team to help visualize strengths and gaps within the team. Established a Sketch and InVision workflow to streamline work between the UX, Design, and Development departments

#### **Senior User Experience Designer**

Spies & Assassins | kbs+ March 2015-November 2015

- Led the responsive redesign of *BMWUSA.com*. Built a modular design system, responsive grid, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes
- Redesigned the sign up flows for the *My BMW* website. Created wireframes, user flows, interaction and technical documentation, and prototypes
- Designed a learning site for digital marketers at Hershey. Conducted user and stakeholder interviews, designed content types, and wireframes

### New York University

October 2008-March 2015

#### **User Experience Specialist**

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014–March 2015

- Designed and developed a new responsive user interface for Sakai—an open source Learning Management System. Wrote new HTML 5 templates and a Sass based CSS framework. Incorporated the user experience and user interface improvements from. NYU Classes
- Redesigned and prototyped a new user interface for NYU's Email Direct—a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

#### **User Experience Designer**

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services
October 2011–August 2014

- Redesigned and developed a new user interface for NYU Classes—their Learning Management System (LMS). The redesign was based on extensive usability testing and research
- Created a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of <u>MediaCommons</u>—a digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media studies

### **UX/UI Skills**

- · Usability Testing, User Interviews, & Personas
- Sketching, Storyboarding, & Paper Prototyping
- Wireframing, Card Sorting, & High-fidelity Prototyping
- Design Systems, Style Guides, & Visual Design

### **Technical Skills**

- Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, InVision, Principle
- Markup (HTML) & Styling (CSS)
- Sass & Compass, Javascript & jQuery, Grunt & Gulp
- Git & SVN, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

#### **Interactive Designer and Developer**

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services
October 2008–October 2011

- Designed and developed <u>MediaCommons</u>—a digital network for professors and post-graduate students—using Drupal
- Established a distinctive look and feel for the MediaCommons network and it's project sites
- Designed and developed two platforms for viewing the digital collections of NYU Libraries. Allowing patrons to view both image based collections—scanned books and photographs—and stream audio and video collections

### Columbia University

August 2001-September 2008

#### **Senior Web Designer and Developer**

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University)

May 2005-September 2008

 Designed and developed educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits

#### Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001–May 2005

- Worked with Columbia University faculty to design and develop interactive eseminars and courses
- Designed and developed interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

### Scholastic

January 2000-May 2001

#### Web Designer

e-Scholastic

- Designed educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- · Designed daily site graphics, interactive quizzes, and educational activities

# **Teaching**

The New School, Fall 2004–Spring 2008

Adjunct faculty member, Media Studies

 Courses: Foundations of Media Design, Digital Video Effects, and Motion Graphics with After Effects

Columbia University, Summer 2005–Summer 2008

Instructor, High School Program

• Course: Digital Filmmaking: From Initial Concept to Final Edit

## Education

1999–2007 **Ph.D. Media & Communication**, *European Graduate School*, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

1998-2001 Certificate in Film Production, The New School, New York, NY

1995–1996 M.Phil. Medieval History, Trinity College, Dublin University, Ireland

1991-1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland